<document>
  <title>Data Model</title>
  <position>3</position>
  <section>
    <docs>
      <![CDATA[
      This section is here to give you an overview on the data model inside
      Radium. You should understand how each different resource interacts with
      the others after reading this section. This section will not go in depth
      into each resource. Refer to each resource's section for in depth
      coverage. 
      ]]>
    </docs>
  </section>
  <section title="Accounts">
    <docs>
      <![CDATA[
      All resources are scoped to a specific account. An account is the
      container for all things in Radium. Users, contacts, groups, and
      everything else all live inside the account. Accounts have owners.
      Owners are responsible for paying the bills for each account. Owners may
      set permissions for other users related to this account. Enabled
      services are stored at the account level. You as the developer never
      interact directly with the account. You only access things through the
      account. You are not allowed to access things side this account. The
      account is your planet and just like man kind you have not unlocked
      "travel to different planets."
      ]]>
    </docs>
  </section>
  <section title="Users">
    <docs>
      <![CDATA[
      Users do actions. They send emails, make todos, create campaigns, manage
      deals, manage contacts, and create groups. They are essentially
      everything! The system is build around users interacting with contacts.
      User's can follow other users, contact, or campaigns. Users are
      organized into teams with someone in charge of the team. Users can be in
      many teams at once. You are only allowed to manage yourself. If you have
      permission you can invite more users into your company's account. You
      can also create deals, record phone calls, messages, add contacts etc.
      ]]>
    </docs>
  </section>
  <section title="Contacts">
    <docs>
      <![CDATA[
      Contacts are the core of Radium. Contacts can be anything! They can be
      people, they can be companies, they can be organizations. They are
      anything you interact with. All resources are somehow related to
      contacts. User can request follow contacts to have things related to
      them added to their feed. Contacts can be put into multiple groups to
      keep them organized. For example, you could organize your contacts into
      "Workers" or "Partners." Contacts also go through the sale pipeline (this
      can be configured). Contacts are automatically moved through the
      pipeline based on their interactions inside Radium. There is more
      discussion on this in the Pipeline section. Contacts must be assigned to
      users. The user is responsible for managing them through the sales
      process. The user allow approves who can view this particular contact's
      feed. Contacts can be extended with extra fields. You can use extra
      fields to add your own particular data to each individual record.
      ]]>
    </docs>
  </section>
  <section title="Groups">
    <docs>
      <![CDATA[
      Groups are a way to organize contacts. Groups can also be extended with
      extra fields. You **do not** interact directly with groups. You can use
      the grouping structure to mimic a Person and Company heirarchy. Groups
      are very free form and are only here for to put contacts in arbitrary
      groups. Groups are like tags but offer more power since they can be
      extended with extra fields.
      ]]>
    </docs>
  </section>
  <section title="Todos">
    <docs>
      <![CDATA[
      Todos are very important! Todos have a description and a date to finish
      it by. Todos can be associated with _anything_ in the system. Todos can
      also have reminders. We also notify you if todos have been reassigned to
      you. People are allowed to add todos for other people as well. Users can
      also comment on todos. The platform will also associate todos with a
      specific contact based on what they're associated with. For example, if
      you make a todo about a meeting with a contact, the todo will be
      associated with the specific contact(s). Another example, if you make a
      todo about a deal, then the todo will be associated with the deal's
      contact. Todos may also be associated with a campaign. Todos may also
      have attachments.
      ]]>
    </docs>
  </section>
  <section title="Deals">
    <docs>
      <![CDATA[
      Deals record financial interactions with a particular contact. Deals go
      through a these states:

      1. Pending
      2. Closed
      3. Paid
      4. Rejected

      The associated contact will move through the pipeline depending on what
      state the deal is. Deals happen with a user and a contact. Deals can
      also be a part of a campaign. Deals can also have attachments.
      ]]>
    </docs>
  </section>
  <section title="Messages (Email, SMS, & IM)">
    <docs>
      <![CDATA[
      Radium can handle many different forms of communication. It can sync SMS
      from your phone and send them. It can sync email from your email account
      and send email using your account. You can also IM people inside your
      own company. Email and SMS can be associated with contacts. IM's are
      only associated with people inside your own company. You cannot IM a
      contact. Sending a message to a contact will move them up a stage in the
      pipeline.
      ]]>
    </docs>
  </section>
  <section title="Phone Calls">
    <docs>
      <![CDATA[
      Phone calls are logged from the user's mobile device. Phone calls have
      specific outcomes which managers can use to track their agent's success
      rate. Phone calls are also associated with call lists. Phone calls
      happen between users and contacts. They can either between a user and
      another or between a contact and a user. Phone calls can have todos
      about them and also be commented on. Calling a contact will move them up
      in the pipeline.
      ]]>
    </docs>
  </section>
  <section title="Meetings">
    <docs>
      <![CDATA[
      Anyone can add a meeting. You can have a meeting with yourself or you
      can choose to invite users or contacts to the meeting. The person who
      added the meeting can choose to cancel or reschedule the meeting. If
      they do this, everyone invited will receive a confirmation notification.
      Individual invitees can decide to confirm or deny their invitation.
      Inviting contacts to meetings will move them up in the pipeline.
      Meetings can also have attachments.
      ]]>
    </docs>
  </section>
  <section title="Call Lists">
    <docs>
      <![CDATA[
      Call Lists contain contacts. Call lists live inside campaigns. All call
      lists must have a name and a call by date. You choose to assign a call
      list to a user when it's created. Then, when the calls are made they
      will be automatically removed from the call list.
      ]]>
    </docs>
  </section>
  <section title="Campaigns">
    <docs>
      <![CDATA[
      Campaigns are a way to group everything else. Contacts, todos, messages,
      meetings, and call lists all live inside campaigns. You can add people
      to a campaign then create things for it. You need a campaign to create a
      call list. Everything else can be associated with a particular campaign.
      If you make a todo (or anything else) it can be associated with a
      campaign. Campaigns have designated start and ends times. A campaign
      also has a specific monetary value it should bring it. This is
      calculated from all the deals with contacts in the campaign. Users can
      request to follow campaigns. The person in charge of the campaign will
      approve these requests. Campaigns also have their own individual
      statistics which can be used for reporting.
      ]]>
    </docs>
  </section>
  <section title="Notes, Comments, & Attachments">
    <docs>
      <![CDATA[
      These resources can be associated with anything. There is
      nothing particularly important about them. They are only used to enhance
      the associated record. They are public by default.
      ]]>
    </docs>
  </section>
  <section title="Extra Fields">
    <docs>
      <![CDATA[
      Extra fields are used to extend individual records. They can be added to
      a specific record or all many records at once. They have a type like:
      email, phone number or general. You can also specify a set to choose
      from. For example you could create an extra field with choices: A, B, C,
      and D. That way when a user changes that extra field it will only allow
      value that are A, B, C, or D. The email and phone number attributes will
      also be used to match phone calls, SMS, and emails to people when
      syncing. Extra fields will also be persisted to external accounts when
      syncing to those accounts.
      ]]>
    </docs>
  </section>
  <section title="Reminders">
    <docs>
      <![CDATA[
      Reminders can be associated with Todos or Meetings. They require a
      specific time to be sent. They can be sent via Email or SMS.
      ]]>
    </docs>
  </section>
  <section title="External Accounts">
    <docs>
      <![CDATA[
      These are Google or Exchange accounts. Changes that happen in Radium
      will be synced back to all the other accounts the user has. Changes that
      happen inside these accounts are synced with Radium.
    ]]></docs>
  </section>
</document>
