<document>
  <title>The Pipeline</title>
  <position>4</position>
  <section>
    <docs>
      <![CDATA[
      The pipeline models the progression of a contact. They enter the system
      as a `lead` and either exit the system as a `customer` or a `dead end`.
      You do not have to manage the pipeline yourself. It happens
      automatically based a user's interaction with that particular person.
      The progression through the pipeline is:

      1. Lead
      2. Prospect
      3. Opportunity
      4. Customer
      5. Dead End

      These states are not serial. They can be skipped. Radium will do it's
      best to adapt to all scenarios. Contacts can have their state changed if
      people desire. However, the automatically pipeline progression should be
      acceptable in most scenarios.
      ]]>
    </docs>
  </section>
  <section title="Leads">
    <docs>
      <![CDATA[
      `Lead` is the default state. If a contact is added **without** a state
      specified they will be a lead. A lead is someone you have not contacted
      or interacted with. A lead represents a chance for your company to make
      money. A lead will become a prospect once they are interacted with. This
      means, sending them a message, inviting them to a meeting, or making a
      todo about them. They can become a dead end if they are uninterested in
      whatever your product is. All states can become dead ends at any time.
      ]]>
    </docs>
  </section>
  <section title="Prospecs">
    <docs>
      <![CDATA[
      `Prospect` means you've interacted with this contact some how. They've
      already been through the lead pool and you're are actively trying to
      start a deal with this person in some fashion. A prospect will become an
      `opportunity` when a deal is added with them.
      ]]>
    </docs>
  </section>
  <section title="Opportunities">
    <docs>
      <![CDATA[
      `Opportunity` means there is open deal with this person. They will
      either become a customer when the deal is paid or dead end if the deal
      is rejected.
      ]]>
    </docs>
  </section>
  <section title="Customers">
    <docs>
      <![CDATA[
      `Customer` is the happy state. This means they've bought whatever your
      selling and now it is up to you to follow up with them or do whatever
      your organization requires to retain them.
      ]]>
    </docs>
  </section>
  <section title="Dead Ends">
    <docs>
      <![CDATA[
      `Dead Ends` are people who are not interested in your product(s) at all.
      They should not be contacted again. For all intensive purposes, you can
      consider them removed from the system. 
      ]]>
    </docs>
  </section>
  <section title="Statistics & Reports">
    <docs>
      <![CDATA[
      Progression through the pipeline is automatically tracked by Radium.
      Radium will use this information to generate all sorts of fancy reports
      (including charts and graphs!) for pipeline states at arbitrary times. We
      are here for all your enterprise needs! (including charts and graphs).
      ]]>
    </docs>
  </section>
</document>
