<document>
  <title>Call Lists</title>
  <position>16</position>
  <section>
    <docs>
      <![CDATA[
      Call Lists represent a list of contacts that need to be called as part
      of a campaign. The calls are assigned to users and made to contacts.
      Adding someone to a call list adds them to their todo list. The
      todo can be reassigned or rescheduled if need be. Call Lists
      can have their own end date which sets the due date for all the todos.
      If a end date is not specified, it will be set from the campaign.
      A contact can be on many different call lists, but cannot be on the same
      one multiple times. Call lists can also be handled automatically
      using our VOIP system.
      ]]>
    </docs>
  </section>
  <section title="Routes & Permissions">
    <docs>
      <![CDATA[
      * `POST /call_lists`
      * `GET /call_lists`
      * `GET /call_lists/:id`
      * `PUT /call_lists/:id'
      * `DELETE /call_lists/:id`

      ### Scoping

      1. You are managing the associated campaign
      2. You are following the associated campaign
      3. You are following any of the user's making the calls
      4. You are following any of the contacts to be called
      5. You are following the user managing the campaign
      6. You are an admin
      ]]>
    </docs>
  </section>
  <section title="Format">
    <docs>
      <![CDATA[
      <dl>
        <dt>description</dt>
        <dd>Text descibing the call list</dd>

        <dt>finish_by</dt>
        <dd>The date all calls should be made by</dd>

        <dt>user</dt>
        <dd>ID for the managing user</dd>

        <dt>campaign</dt>
        <dd>ID for the associated campaign</dd>

        <dt>todos</dt>
        <dd>IDs for all the todos</dd>

        <dt>pending_todos</dt>
        <dd>IDs for all the unmade calls</dd>

        <dt>overdue_todos</dt>
        <dd>IDs for all the late calls</dd>

        <dt>users</dt>
        <dd>IDs for all the users making the calls</dd>

        <dt>contacts</dt>
        <dd>IDs for all the contacts on the call list</dd>
      </dd>
      ]]>
    </docs>
    <reference title="Call List Format">
      <![CDATA[
      ```javascript
      {
        "id": 1,
        "created_at": "2011-12-28T14:26:24Z",
        "updated_at": "2011-12-28T14:26:24Z",
        "description": "Call List 1",
        "finish_by": "2012-01-04T14:26:22Z",
        "user": 5,,
        "campaign:" 3,
        "todos": [

        ],
        "pending_todos": [

        ],
        "finished_todos": [

        ],
        "overdue_todos": [

        ],
        "users": [

        ],
        "contacts": [

        ]
      }
      ```
      ]]>
    </reference>
  </section>
  <section title="Creating a Call List">
    <docs>
      <![CDATA[
      **NOTE**: this functionality is a work in progress. There is some
      special logic that goes into creating a call list that has not
      been implemented yet. This specically pertains to addings groups
      to call lists. 

      You can add contacts and groups to call lists. You can only add
      them if they have a phone number. The server will check for duplicates
      to ensure that the same person is not called twice.

      Groups are handled differently than contacts. Groups have primary 
      contacts. If a primary contact is present, they will be added to
      the call list. If a primaty contact is not present, a new contact
      will be added with the group's contact phone number. Then, you can
      fill in that contact's information when you make the call.
      ]]>
    </docs>
  </section>
</document>
