<document>
  <title>Meetings</title>
  <position>16</position>
  <section>
    <docs>
      <![CDATA[
      Meetings are controlled by a user. They do not need to have anyone
      coming to the meeting. Users and contacts can be added to meetings.
      You invite people by sending their email address. The server will
      conect the dots to associate the users and contacts. If no one can
      be found matching the email, then a new contact will be created 
      for you to fill in their information. The server will send invitations
      via email. Invitations are handled individually. The meeting's organizer
      will be notified of acceptance and rejections. The organizer can
      also reschedule or cancel the meeting. If the meeting is rescheduled,
      all the people will be notified and be asked to reconfirm. Refer
      to the invitation section for managing individual invitations.
      ]]>
    </docs>
  </section>
  <section title="Routes & Permissions">
    <docs>
      <![CDATA[
      * `POST /meetings`
      * `GET /meetings`
      * `GET /meetings/:id`
      * `PUT /meetings/:id`
      * `DELETE /meetings/:id`
      * `PUT /meetings/:id/reschedule`
      * `PUT /meetings/:id/cancel`

      ### Scoping

      1. You are in charge of the meeting
      2. You are invited to the meeting
      3. Any of the invited contacts are assigned to you
      4. You are following any of the invited contacts
      5. You are an admin
      ]]>
    </docs>
  </section>
  <section>
    <![CDATA[
    ### Rescheduling, Cancelling, and Deleting

    These are all different actions. Rescheduling is a special update.
    It works the same way as the regular `PUT /meetings/:id` route
    except will send out notifications to everyone regardless of
    if the time changed or anything like that. Cancelling works
    the same way. You can always reschedule a cancelled meeting.
    A meeting will continue to exist in the system if it's cancelled.
    Deleting a meeting will remove it from the system entirely and **will not**
    send any notifications. It is up to you to decide which functionality
    to use by a use case by use case basis.
    ]]>
  </section>
  <section title="Inviting People">
    <![CDATA[
    You can add more people to the meeting one the `POST` and `PUT` routes. 
    Specify a `invite` parameter which contains an array of valid email addresses.
    Invitations will be created and notifications sent out by the server. 
    You are not allowed to create invitations manually. If you want to invite
    more people to an existing meeting use the `PUT /meetings/:id` route
    with a `invite` parameter.
    ]]>
  </section>
  <section title="Format">
    <docs>
      <![CDATA[
      <dl>
        <dt>topic</dt>
        <dd>
          <strong>Required</strong><br/>
          Text describing the meetings purpose
        </dd>

        <dt>starts_at</dt>
        <dd>
          <strong>Required</strong><br/>
          Time when it starts
        </dd>

        <dt>ends_at</dt>
        <dd>
          <strong>Required</strong><br/>
          Time when it ends
        </dd>

        <dt>location</dt>
        <dd>Can be an address, can be anything. 
          Example: <code>the office</code>, or <code>123 Example St.</code>
        </dd>

        <dt>user</dt>
        <dd>ID for the user managing this meeting</dd>

        <dt>contacts</dt>
        <dd>IDs for all the invited contacts</dd>

        <dt>users</dt>
        <dd>ID's for all the invited users including the organizer</dd>

        <dt>activities</dt>
        <dd>ID's for all activites in the meeting's feed</dd>

        <dt>invitations</dt>
        <dd>All the invitations for the meeting. See the invitation 
          section for more details</dd>
      </dl>
      ]]>
    </docs>
    <reference title="Meeting Format">
      <![CDATA[
      ```javascript
      {
        "id": 2,
        "created_at": "2011-12-28T14:26:26Z",
        "updated_at": "2011-12-28T14:26:26Z",
        "topic": "Meeting 2",
        "location": "The office",
        "starts_at": "2011-12-28T15:26:22Z",
        "ends_at": "2011-12-28T16:26:22Z",
        "user": 5,
        "contacts": [

        ],
        "users": [
          29
        ],
        "activities": [
          32
        ],
        "invitations": [
          {
            "id": 3,
            "created_at": "2011-12-28T14:26:26Z",
            "updated_at": "2011-12-28T14:26:26Z",
            "state": "confirmed",
            "hash_key": "f9e7128044e00d3f7cd881fe76a3b079c8450c09",
            "meeting": 2,
            "user": 29
          }
        ]
      }
      ```
      ]]>
    </reference>
  </section>
  <section>
    <docs>
      <![CDATA[
      You can specify the `invite` parameter to send invitations.
      ]]>
    </docs>
    <reference title="Create a Meeting">
      <![CDATA[
      `POST /meetings`

      ### Parameters

      ```javascript
      {
        "developer_api_key": "foo",
        "user_api_key": "bar",
        "meeting: {
          "topic": "Q3",
          "starts_at": "2011-12-28T15:26:22Z",
          "ends_at": "2011-12-28T16:26:22Z",
          "invite": [ 'mycoworker@company.com', 'james@microsoft.com']
        }
      }
      ```
      ]]>
    </reference>
  </section>
</document>
